Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/saajansangha (LinkedIn)

Top Skills CSS

JavaScript PHP

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Sonny Sangha

Youtuber/Mentor & Founder and CEO of Zero to Full Stack Hero United Kingdom

Summary

I've been coding for over 10 years now. As a Full Stack developer I've worked both with startups and large corporations to help build & scale their companies. Along the journey I realised my passion existed in helping others excel and pursue their dreams as upcoming full-stack developers. With this passion, I have now trained thousand's of developers across the globe. Through live coaching sessions on Youtube, I have accumulated several MILLION's of views where I demonstrate how to apply developer skills in a range of cool builds and challenges.

I just launched 'ZERO to FULL STACK HERO', the world's best developer community

Be a part of the amazing PAPA Community today, head over to www.papareact.com and i'll see you inside!

Experience

Sonny Sangha
Youtuber/Mentor & CEO of PAPA by Papa React
December 2020 - Present (2 years)
Subscribe to 'Sonny Sangha' on YouTube!

Private Tutor
Private Computing/Maths Tutor
October 2014 - Present (8 years 2 months)

- I privately teach Computing and Business IT students who needs assistance during my spare time, this has encouraged me to be very efficient with my time as I need to balance my work flow with such activities without depreciating my work quality in the progress.
- In order to obtain tutees, I had to display my knowledge and give the tutees faith in that I was capable in assisting them and helping them improve their

own work, I was able to do so by simply assisting them in the completion of their own work to a high standard, this displayed my skills quite well.

Clever Programmer
Team Member & React Specialist
April 2020 - December 2020 (9 months)
London, England, United Kingdom

Lindar Media Software Engineer November 2019 - April 2020 (6 months) St Albans, United Kingdom

Tesco Software Dev Engineer II February 2019 - November 2019 (10 months) London, United Kingdom

Birdie
Full Stack Developer
February 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 1 month)
London, United Kingdom

Tipple Ltd Cofounder September 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 2 months) London, United Kingdom

NELFT NHS Foundation Trust PC Rollout Engineer June 2016 - August 2016 (3 months) Goodmayes

Responsible for upgrading 400-500 old HP NHS Desktops to new Desktops which are capable of handling the latest required security requirements of the NELFT NHS foundation trust. The computers are situated at 200+ sites within Essex and London.

I am required to configure, transport, deploy and replace the current legacy hardware with the new upgraded hardware.

Responsible for handling delivery and asset management of new PC's, and also to ensure that all asset management records have been updated to indicate the replacing of old legacy desktops/laptops.

Utilising Microsoft Sysprep to prepare an installation of Windows for duplication, auditing, and customer delivery.

Reimaging existing legacy hardware so that it can be redeployed and reused.

Utilising Microsoft Active Directory to manage deployed PC's so that the correct policies are applied according to the site and location in which the desktop is to be situated in.

Responsible for troubleshooting and solving Network, TCP/IP and DNS issues and concerns across the NHS during the rollout project.

JS Construction Labour and Admin Management July 2007 - June 2016 (9 years) [PART-TIME]

- I am able to complete numerous administration tasks such as creating invoices and using my IT skills in creating Excel Spreadsheets when calculating expenses and profits.
- This job requires myself to carry out labour-intensive tasks such as construction and maintenance within a team.

Ambition House

Partner

November 2013 - September 2015 (1 year 11 months)

- Ambition House provided me with an optimistic and productive environment to develop my skills in, usually working in small teams of coders, graphic designers and business students.
- Here I have developed my programming knowledge working in small teams to design new potential applications.

• Being a partner of AH has allowed me to build my confidence and interpersonal skills hugely, with regular workshops and networking opportunities, my skillset is endlessly being developed and added to.

University of Kent

1 year 11 months

Student Mentor

September 2014 - June 2015 (10 months)

- I'm responsible for aiding stage 1 students in weekly workshops held by the university-computing department.
- I have learnt a substantial amount during my time helping others progress through their work, as although the content is something I have already covered, it gives me a chance to build upon my current knowledge. This has proven to help me an extreme amount when completing my own coursework.

Student Ambassador

August 2013 - June 2015 (1 year 11 months)

- I aim to deliver a positive image for the University of Kent through volunteering and job placements in various areas (University tours, UCAS open days, External volunteering etc.)
- I have delivered engaging higher education information to large audiences, usually of a younger age group.
- One of my roles includes persuading and engaging upcoming students to the life and social aspects once arriving at the University of Kent.
- I have to frequently communicate and engage with a range and diverse selection of age groups, from as young as year 3 students to senior students and public members.
- I am able to spontaneously adapt to carrying out a new job or requirement, as this is a constantly engaging and forever changing role, it too requires a large amount of time management.

Currys

Sales Assistant

July 2010 - August 2010 (2 months)

I assisted with customer sales and customer relations.

• Stock control and Warehouse Management.

Education

University of Kent

Master of Science (MSc), Advanced Computer Science · (2016 - 2017)

University of Kent

Computing (Bsc Hons), Computer Science · (2013 - 2016)

Beal High School Sixth Form

High School, Mathematics A2, Biology A2, Computing A2 & Chemistry AS · (2011 - 2013)

Beal High School Secondary School

High School · (2006 - 2011)